adam.com 2007-12-23

# A.D.A.M. Inc. :: Complete Online Health Content Solutions :: Privacy Statement

A.D.A.M.'s Privacy Statement explains how we manage information obtained from you. Throughout this document, we have highlighted various terms and linked them to our Glossary or the relevant section of this website.

**Licensed Content **

A.D.A.M. content is licensed to other organizations that make our content available to consumers. A.D.A.M. is firmly committed to respecting the privacy of individuals. Any information that we gather is protected from misappropriation and misuse.

A.D.A.M. collects certain types of user data, including anonymous aggregate data and anonymous individual data. Aggregate data describes all user data as a whole, rather than the data of specific individuals. Collected data may include topics that people view, browsers they used, time and length content is used, health risk assessment data, and similar types of data. This data may be used by A.D.A.M. or its customers to understand what health information is used most frequently and how users are accessing the information. 

In addition, some organizations that license A.D.A.M. content provide login accounts to secure, personalized websites. A.D.A.M. may provide these organizations with data that is specific to an individual login account, although A.D.A.M. itself does not store personally identifiable information (such as names and phone numbers) and has no way of knowing who an individual user is. Consumers should review the privacy policies of the organizations from which they access A.D.A.M. content to see how individual data may be used. A.D.A.M. is not responsible for the privacy practices of organizations that have licensed A.D.A.M. information.

**Opt-In **

A.D.A.M. may receive Personal Identifiable Information (PII) via forms located on our corporate web site, or through purchasing a product through our online store. If you, the website user, complete and submit your PII via our online forms to obtain product information, or through the store to purchase a product, you are "opting-in" to provide us with your PII, and accept our Privacy Statement and policies and procedures for handling PII. This action may result in being contacted by an A.D.A.M. sales, editorial or support professional. 

By completing any of our online forms, A.D.A.M. may collect any or all of the information found in section "Information Obtained" section of this document. A.D.A.M. will not use your PII for any use other than stated or intended.

**Opt-Out **

You, the website user, may wish to opt-out of providing us PII by not completing the online form(s) for product information, and may contact the company directly via fax or phone. Please select the "[Contact A.D.A.M.](http://www.adam.com/contact_adam.html)" link to find an alternative way to contact us. If you have previously contacted A.D.A.M. and provided PII, you may request to have the information removed, by selecting the appropriate checkbox located on any of our online contact forms, such as our [contact sales page](http://www.adam.com/contact_sales.html). 

**Information Obtained**

By completing any of our online forms, A.D.A.M. may collect the following information:  

  * Company/Organization
  * Company Description
  * Prefix/Title
  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Address
  * City
  * State/Province
  * Zip Code 
  * Personal Password
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number
  * Current Customer
  * Hear about us

In addition, for purchases through our online store, the following may be obtained:  

  * Name on Credit Card
  * Credit Card Number
  * Credit Card Verification Code
  * Card Type
  * Expiration Date

**Passive Tracking Mechanisms**

Some A.D.A.M. products utilize passive tracking mechanisms in the form of session "cookies". In specific products, these mechanisms track user selections so either an online store order can be processed or customized results pages can be provided. 

In addition, log files that track and compile data for websites are accessed by WebTrends Software and periodically analyzed to monitor trends of those individuals who visit our website. General information, including pages accessed, the amount of time accessing pages, browser, and operating system, used are analyzed.

**Personal Identifiable Information (PII)**

Personal Identifiable Information (PII) is information that may be used to identify an individual, including, without limitation, your first and last name, your home or other physical address, your electronic mail address, which Internet address you go to, what browser you are using, and other similar information (collectively, "Personal Information").

A.D.A.M. receives potential client PII via forms located on the corporate web site. By using these forms you hereby agree to this privacy policy and "Opt- In", providing us with PII. Upon form completion, the user will click the send or submit button. The PII is sent to an A.D.A.M. Sales, Editorial or support associate via unsecured e-mail. A.D.A.M. does not collect or ask for any specific information that warrants increased security and/or encryption. Contact and product information is collected to assist our sales professionals in informing potential clients of our product offerings. If the user is not interested in submitting information via the provided web form, they may contact us via regular mail, phone or fax.

The request and PII is reviewed and qualified. The PII is entered into either the Editorial Comments database that assists us in reviewing past or present comments or through a secure, third party application (Sales Contact Database) designed to track potential, current and past sales clients. 

Using the A.D.A.M. Online Store, PII is submitted through placing an order, or a request more information. PII is submitted by the end user through the online form to process the order, is encrypted and sent to our third party vendor that processes the credit card, secures the payment and notifies A.D.A.M. that the transaction was successful or denied. If successful, our secure order tracking system displays the order to select accounting, shipping personnel and select managers. The shipping associate fulfills the order for shipment, selects a shipping company (UPS, FedEx, or DHL), shipping method and securely submits the necessary information needed to ship the order.

A.D.A.M. does not knowingly collect personal information from any person under the age of 13. We are committed to protecting the privacy of children, and this website is not designed or intended for children under the age of 13.

**PII - Disclosure **

The Editorial Comments Database is accessible by select members of the A.D.A.M. editorial department, and used to review the past and present feedback provided to us by clients and end users. 

Information stored in the third party Sales Contact application is available to all sales and marketing personnel as well as members of the Client Services team and select members of managment. Our third party provider upholds the same rigorous security guidelines followed by A.D.A.M and our employees.

Information stored in the secure online store database is available to select accounting, shipping personnel as well as select members of management. For shipping, PII is also sent to our secure third party vendors that process the credit card transactions as well as ship your product. These third party vendors uphold the same rigorous security guidelines followed by A.D.A.M and our employees.

**PII - Retention: **

A.D.A.M., Inc. receives PII via online forms located on the corporate web site or through orders submitted through the online store. This information is stored in a secure database indefinitely, until a time that a request is submitted to A.D.A.M. to request it's removal. (see "PII- How to Modify" below").

**PII - Users Rights: **

Personal Identifiable Information (PII) is information that may be used to identify an individual, including, without limitation, your first and last name, your home or other physical address, your electronic mail address, which Internet address you go to, what browser you are using, and other similar information (collectively, "Personal Information"). 

If you have requested information from us using one of our online forms, you have sent us PII. If you wish to have your PII removed from our database, you may contact us and request it to be removed. (see "PII- How to Modify" below").

**PII - Maintenance**

A.D.A.M. receives PII via forms located on our corporate web site. This information is stored in a secure database indefinitely, until a time that a request is submitted to A.D.A.M. to request modification or removal. Information is maintained and backed up by either the VP of Engneering or by our third party vendor, who upholds the same rigorous security guidelines followed by A.D.A.M and our employees.

**PII - Modification**

You are provided the opportunity to "modify" contact information by submitting a request via e-mail to modify or delete your PII. The link is located below the Information request forms, located at either:

Clicking on the link will provide you with the ability to send an e-mail to the A.D.A.M. to modify or remove your PII.

**PII - Limitations**

A.D.A.M. has the ability to modify or remove your PII from our proprietary Editorial Comments or Sales Contact Databases. Information collected may reside in a back-up archive until a point that the back up is either written over and or destroyed. 

A.D.A.M. does not have the ability to modify or remove your PII from third party secure payment or shipping databases. Information submitted to these entities may reside on their servers indefinitely.

**Glossary**

**Cookies -** A small data file that is stored on the hard drive of the computer you use to view a Web site. Cookies are placed on the user's computer and are accessible only by the party or site that placed the Cookie. Cookies can contain pieces of Personally Identifiable Information (PII). These Cookies often are used to make the site easier to use. For example, if you check a form box to authorize that we store your username on your computer so that you don't have to enter it each time you visit the site, it's stored in a Cookie on your computer.

**Personal Health Information (PHI) -** Individually identifiable health information that is transmitted or maintained by electronic media or is transmitted or maintained in any other form or medium. "Health information" is any information relating to the past, present, or future physical or mental health or condition of an individual.

**Personal Identifiable Information (PII) -** Information that may be used to identify an individual, including, without limitation, your first and last name, your home or other physical address, your age and income, your electronic mail address, which Internet address you go to, what browser you are using, and other similar information (collectively, "Personal Information")
